Professional Summary

Software Engineer with 2 years of professional experience in software applications development with multiple tech stacks in front-end and back-end development. Enthusiastic to solve and get wide exposure with the challenges from diverse work culture and organizations.

Work Experience

JerseySTEM February 2024 - Present

Software Engineer

Remote

- Volunteering in the software development team as an aim to provide education support for 2600 middle school girl children. Utilized google suite to implement user data automation with **Javascript** using **Google appscripts**.
- Developing APIs for Read from google sheet, Write to google sheet using **C#**, **ASP** .**Net Core** framework resulted in reducing the code reuse upto 20%.
- Implemented Robotics Process Automation(RPA) bots to automate several daily business activities that could help reducing 30% of the daily time for the JIRA board.

Medintu Solutions August 2021 – July 2022

Software Engineer

- Orchestrated 15% enhancement of a web application through the strategic integration of HTML, CSS, Javascript, React JS, C#, ASP .Net Core, and PostgreSQL services, resulting in streamlined processes and improved user experience
- Successfully designed APIs utilizing RESTful APIs for optimized data interaction between new communication portal and database, reducing data processing time by 30%.
- Improved the web application scalability by deploying with Amazon Web Services infrastructure, resulting to 25% reduced latency and increase in the web application responsiveness.
- Demonstrated proficiency in GIT source code management, leading to a 20% decrease in deployment time and a 15% boost in version control precision.
- Development of web application has reduced end-to-end onboarding time for business management by 40%, streamlining design and business intelligence.

Zebo Feb 2021 – July 2021

Software Engineering Intern

- Designed aging signs user interface using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React JS impacting 25% reduction in form validation errors and 15% improvement in user experience.
- Implemented agile development using Scrum, reducing development cycles by 20% and improving collaboration.
- Implemented containerization of web application utilizing Docker and Kubernetes services, resulting in 30% amplified scalability of the application.
- Implemented database objects like Tables, Views, Stored Procedures, User Functions seamlessly integrated them into web components, achieving a 40% decrease in database query response time.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, C#, Java

Web Development: Html, Css, JavaScript, React, Django, Flask, REST APIS, ASP .Net Developer Tools: Jenkins, Maven, Git, Junit, Jira, Selenium, Eye automate, Agile, Linux

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Cloud technolgies: Amazon Web Services(EC2, ELB, RDS, and S3), Docker

Big Data frameworks: Hadoop, Spark, Kafka

Projects

Web application for movie name prediction based on movie scripts | Python, NLP, Jupyter Notebook

- Engineered and led the deployment of a groundbreaking web application to analyze text from 50 movie scripts, and predicting the movie names from that text.
- Trained a machine learning model using movie scripts data to predict movie names with text from movie script as user input data. Selected and deployed the model with 80% prediction accuracy.

Mobile Application Development | Flutter, Android studio

- Developed the "Pass the Challenge" game application during a university mobile application technologies workshop using Flutter, Figma for front end development and Android-SDK, Java programming language, and MongoDB for backend server implementation to store user stories. Achieved 2nd place out of 25 teams in the workshop.
- Conducted comprehensive real-world testing of the Pass the challenge game application in a university setting, included actionable feedback from 250 student participants via survey questionnaires to drive iterative improvements and enhanced user experience.

Education

University at Buffalo, The State University of New York

August 2022 - January 2024

Master of science in Computer Science & Engineering

Buffalo, NY

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Project Management, Machine Learning, Modern Networking Concepts

Blekinge Institute of Technology

August 2020 - July 2021

Bachelor of Science in Computer science

Karlskrona,Sweden

JNTU Anantapur

August 2017 - July 2020

Bachelor of Technology in Computer science and Engineering

Anantapur, India

Relevant Coursework: Theory of Computation, Computer Networks, Software Engineering

Relevant Coursework: Cloud Computing, Mobile Application Development, Software Testing

Publications

Published a research paper on "prediction of movie name from plot of a movie as user input", under the supervision of Dr. Suejb Memeti.